This is not good.
（デイダラ）これヤバいな うん
んん…
It's over...
（カンクロウ）終わったな
（砂すなの里さとの忍たち）ああ
Just what you'd expect
from Kazekage-sama!
（砂の里の忍）さすが風影かぜかげ様だ
Yeah. This village will be safe
（砂の里の忍）ああ 風影様さえ
いてくれれば この里も安心だな
as long as we have
Kazekage-sama!
（カンクロウ）フッ
Hold on!
いや…
（デイダラ）ふん
（デイダラ）ああ
うう…
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
（デイダラ）ああ
うう…
ふんっ
ええい ウザい砂だな うん
This sand's such
a pain in the neck.
（カンクロウ）バカめ フッ…
You fool...!
我愛羅があらの砂から逃げられるものか
Do you really think you can
get away from Gaara's sand?!
The Kazekage
Stands Tall!
I never thought this would be
my reason for losing...
（はたけカカシ）
まさか これが
敗因になるとはな
（うずまきナルト）ヘヘヘッ フフン
（カカシ）さっさと最後まで
読んどけば よかった
I should've just gone ahead
and finished the book...
アッハハハ
But how can you even
read such a boring book?!
でもカカシ先生も よく そんな
つまんない本 読めるよな
（カカシ）え？
Huh?
（ナルト）
俺もエロ仙人に貸してもらったけど
あんまり つまんないんで...
The Pervy Sage loaned it to me,
but it was so boring
I didn't even make it ten pages.
10ページも読んでないってばよ
（カカシ）え？
もちろんオチなんか知らないってば
So of course, I don't know
how the book ends.
（カカシ）ああ…
あ… うん
Even without Naruto knowing
the ending of the book...
（春野はるのサクラ）例えナルトがオチを
知らなくても カカシ先生なら
we figured you'd respond
if we mentioned the name,
「イチャイチャタクティクス」の
名前を出すだけで
"Make-Out Tactics".
反応すると思ったの
Pretty good strategy, huh?
いい作戦でしょ
（カカシ）ええ… ああ
（綱手つなで）２人の成長
しかと見せてもらったぞ
You two certainly showed me
some growth.
（ナルト）あん？
（サクラ）うん？
Master!
師匠
Kakashi, do you have
something to say?
（綱手）カカシ 何か
言うことは あるか？
Well, they did a great job
taking the bells away from me, so...
（カカシ）まあ見事に
鈴も取られた訳ですし
Yes.
（綱手）うん
（サクラ･ナルト）うん？
What're you talking about?
なんの話だってばよ？
We're talking about
your status for the future.
（シズネ）
今後の あなたたち２人の
処遇に関することですよ
な… 俺たちの処遇？
Our status...?
（綱手）うずまきナルト
（ナルト）は？
- Uzumaki Naruto!
- Huh?
Answer me.
（シズネ）返事は？
（ナルト）ああ おう
Y-Yeah!
Haruno Sakura!
（綱手）春野サクラ
（サクラ）はい
Yes!
The two of you and...
（綱手）お前たち２人と
はたけカカシ
Hatake Kakashi...
The three of you shall
form Team Kakashi!
この３名によりカカシ班を編成する
（サクラ）カカシ班
（ナルト）あのさあ あのさあ
Team Kakashi...
S-Say, what does that mean?
それって どういうこと
だってばよ？
The two of you will form
a team with me
（カカシ）これからお前たち２人は
この俺と一緒に 任務を
こなしていくチームになる
and we'll carry out
missions together.
（ナルト）はあ？
That's what this means.
（カカシ）…ということだ
It's not like the old days.
昔と違い 今は もう
先生でも生徒でもない
We're no longer teacher
and students.
We will work together as
equal Leaf Shinobi. Got it?
対等な木こノ葉はの忍として
つきあっていく いいな
Sure! I got it!
（ナルト）
おう 分かってるってばよ
（自来也じらいや）フフッ
（バキ）カンクロウ
（カンクロウ）ああ？
Kankuro!
Is Gaara-sama fighting right now?!
Where is he?
（バキ）
戦っているのは我愛羅様か？
どこにいる？
Yeah.
（カンクロウ）ええ あそこに…
He's up there...
（砂の里の忍たち）ああ
Gaara...
（バキ）我愛羅
（デイダラ）はあ！
Sand Coffin...
（我愛羅）砂瀑柩さばくきゅう
He did it...
（砂の里の忍）やった
- He did it!
- Yeah!
（砂の里の忍）やったぞ
すげえぜ 風影様
Kazekage-sama is amazing!
（デイダラ）うう…
クッ 逃したか
Did he get away...?!
That guy sure is lucky...!
（カンクロウ）
あいつ 運のいいヤツだ
Not bad.
やるねえ ふんっ
I get it.
（デイダラ）なるほど
The sand he used to
crush my hand
おいらの腕を潰した砂は
砂漠から持ち上げた
is much faster and more powerful
普通の砂とは
スピードもパワーも違うな
than ordinary sand taken
from the desert...
According to our information...
情報じゃ ヤツは常に
一定量の砂を持ち歩く
He always carries with him
a fixed amount of sand...
つまり その砂だけは
In other words,
only that sand has been...
specially created
あらかじめ大量のチャクラを
練り込んであり 特別製って訳だ
with a large amount
of Chakra built up inside...
そいつが とっさの防御に
使う砂であり
That's the sand he uses
for quick defense...
as well instant attacks.
瞬時の攻撃に使う砂って訳だ
What did they call it again...?
なんて言ったっけかな？
（デイダラ）ん 思い出した
I remember now!
It's the "Ultimate Defense"
絶対防御だ
That's the "Ultimate Defense" sand...
あれこそ絶対防御とやらの砂であり
フッ
In other words,
（デイダラ）つまり 今
あそこに開いている穴の分の砂が
the sand from that hole is
what crushed my arm...
おいらの腕を握りつぶした訳だ
アハッ
I've only got a little bit
of clay left...
（デイダラ）
もう粘土が少ししかねえや
I underestimated him...
甘くみてた 準備不足ってやつかな
What you'd call,
"not prepared enough".
ふん サソリの旦那の
言う通りだね こりゃ
This is just as
the good man Sasori said...
Will just that bag be enough?
（サソリ）
その袋だけで大丈夫なのか？
Our opponent will be
using the Jinchuriki...
相手は人柱力じんちゅうりきを使うんだぜ
I've only enough left for
one more homing-type...
（デイダラ）
もう 追尾タイプが１発分と
and my specialty as well.
オハコも これしか
残ってないぞ うん
I think...
やっぱ 里を壊そう
I'll destroy this village, after all.
ふん
For crying out loud...
（サソリ）ったく
How long is that Deidara going to
make me wait?
いつまで待たせる気だ
デイダラのヤツ
I told him I don't like waiting...
俺は待つのが嫌いだって
言ったろうが
Kazekage-sama...
（男性）風影様…
Black clothing and
a red cloud pattern...!
（砂の里の忍）黒い衣に赤い雲模様
Judging from that appearance,
あの姿からみるに 風影様の相手は
暁あかつきという組織の一員だと思われます
the enemy Kazekage-sama
is fighting against
is likely a member of the organization
called the "Akatsuki".
I knew it.
やっぱりな
Kankuro.
（バキ）カンクロウ
（カンクロウ）ん なんです？
What is it?
Gaara's even using
his "Ultimate Defense" sand
（バキ）我愛羅が絶対防御の
砂まで出して戦っている
in this fight.
I think it's safe to assume
the enemy is a formidable one.
敵は相当の手練てだれと
考えて間違いない
For the time being,
一応 我愛羅の暴走も
考えに入れておけ
we need to consider that
Gaara could lose control.
な…
守鶴しゅかくが出てきたときの
シナリオも必要だ
We need to be ready
in case Shukaku appears.
The villagers will be in danger.
里の者たちが危険だ
（カンクロウ）
ハッ それは もうありませんよ
That won't happen anymore.
Gaara will not harm
the people of this village.
我愛羅は里の者を傷つけたりしない
Never!
絶対に
Gaara, give it up.
我愛羅 思いとどまれ
I don't want to say this,
こんなことは言いたくないが
but you're nothing but
a frightening weapon to the village...
里にとって お前は
恐るべき兵器でしかない
It'll just be a struggle
for you
いまさら俺たちから離れて
to join a regular unit
at this point.
正規部隊に入るなんて
きついだけじゃん
The superiors don't think
well of you.
お前を よく思っていない
上役ばかりだし
And a majority of the village
is scared of you.
里の大半も お前に対して
恐怖心を抱いている
I know that...
（我愛羅）分かっている
（カンクロウ）あ…
I know that...
（我愛羅）
分かっているが 待っているだけでは
もっと大きな苦しみに また襲われる
but I will be overcome
with an even greater suffering
if I just wait around...
I just have to work hard and
carve out a future for myself.
努力し みずから
切り開くしかないんだ
１人きりの孤独な道に逃げずに
And I must not run away
from my path of solitude.
If I do that, someday...
そうすれば いつか…
Someday... I can be like him...
いつか あいつのように…
So as a Sand Shinobi,
だから 俺は砂の１人の
忍として風影を目指す
I will strive to become
the Kazekage.
To live... bonded with this village.
この里に つながり生きるために
Gaara...
我愛羅…
I want to work hard...
and be acknowledged by others.
（我愛羅）努力し 他者から
認められる存在になりたい
Uzumaki Naruto made
me believe that...
うずまきナルトを見て そう思った
Having bonds with others...
他者との つながり
I only knew hate
and malice up until now.
俺にとって それは今まで
憎しみと殺意でしかなかった
しかし あいつが
あそこまでして言う
But now, there's something
I understand about those bonds.
つながりとは なんなのか
He went so far to tell me about.
今ごろになって 俺にも
少し分かったことがある
I understand that pain,
sadness... and happiness...
苦しみや悲しみ 喜びも
can be shared with others.
（我愛羅）ほかの誰かと
分かち合うことができるのだと
Uzumaki Naruto...
うずまきナルト
I learned that through fighting
and getting to know him.
あいつと戦い触れ合うことで
それを教わった気がする
He knew of the same pain
as me.
あいつは俺と同じ
苦しみを知っていた
And he taught me that I could
change the path of my life.
そして 生きる道を変えることが
できることを教えてくれた
Someday, I want to feel needed
by someone.
俺も いつか誰からも
必要とされる存在になりたい
Not as a frightening weapon...
恐るべき兵器としてではなく
but as the Kazekage
of the Hidden Sand Village.
砂隠れの風影として
There are people who need you.
（カンクロウ）
誰からも必要とされている
You're the Kazekage
of the Hidden Sand!
砂隠れの風影だ
Gaara-sama!
Kazekage-sama!
Hang in there!
Gee, you guys sure got strong.
（カカシ）いやあ しかし
お前らも強くなったね
I never thought you'd really
be able to get the bells...
まさか本当に鈴
取られちゃうとはね
（ナルト）ヘヘヘッ
I just might've surpassed you,
Kakashi-sensei.
俺ってば カカシ先生
追い越しちゃったかもよ？
Why're you talking all big?!
（サクラ）
何 言ってんのよ 偉そうに
（カカシ）
フフッ まっ でもなんだ
Well, but I'm still pretty young,
you see...
俺だって まだまだ若いからな
The other day, I developed
an incredible new Jutsu...
こないだも ある すごい
新術を開発したんだが…
And it's pretty incredible, you see...
Oh, that's right.
（ナルト）あっ そうだよ
I haven't had any Ichiraku Ramen
since I got back!
まだ帰ってきて一楽ラーメン
行ってねえってばよ
Oh, I'm also pretty hungry
（サクラ）
ああ あたしも きのうからの
演習で ちょっとペコペコ
from all that training exercise
since yesterday.
（ナルト）よっしゃあ
一楽ラーメン直行だってばよ
All right! Let's make a beeline
for Ichiraku Ramen!
Right!
（サクラ）うん
They used to be so cute
and react to everything back in the day...
（カカシ）昔は なんにでも
いちいちリアクションしてくれる
カワイイヤツらだったのになあ
（カカシ）ん！
As promised,
I leave Naruto in your care.
（自来也）約束どおり
ナルトは お前に預けるからのォ
It's my first Ichiraku Ramen in ages!
（ナルト）久しぶりの
一楽ラーメンだ
It'll be Kakashi-sensei's treat!
（サクラ）カカシ先生のおごり
- Treat! Treat!
（ナルト･サクラ）おごり おごり
The actions of the Akatsuki
are gaining momentum...
そろそろ暁の動きも
活発になってきたからのォ
I'm heading off to gather information.
これから わしは情報収集に回る
See you around.
じゃあな
Kakashi-sensei!
（サクラ）カカシ先生
Huh?
（カカシ）うん？
It's been settled that
（ナルト）ここはカカシ先生に
おごってもらうって決まったってばよ
you're going to treat us
to some ramen!
Hurry up!
（サクラ）早く 早く
Sorry, guys!
（カカシ）悪いなあ
I have to create and turn in
the unit list for the new team!
俺は これから新チームの
招待リストを作って
提出しなきゃならんから
See you.
これにてドロン
I'm gone.
Oh! He ran away!
（ナルト）あっ 逃げた
He said something about a unit list...
あんなこと言って 本の続きが
気になってるだけよ たぶん
but he's probably just wondering
what happens next in... his book...
That means...
（ナルト）ってことは
（サクラ）ん？
アッハハハ…
Then how about we go
on a date, just the two of us?
じゃあ これから２人っきりで
あの デート…
That's fine. But you're treating.
いいけど 全て おごりね
Oh...
あ…
You could at least pay
for half of the ramen...
せめてラーメン代
半分だけでも出してくれると…
No way!
（サクラ）ダメ
Convene all members
for an emergency meeting!
（バキ）総員に非常招集をかける
（砂の里の忍）はっ
Yes, sir!
You secure the reservoir.
Take two units with you!
（バキ）貴様は貯水池の警護だ
（バキ）２小隊 連れていけ
（砂の里の忍）はっ
Yes, sir.
Seal off the roads in sector A!
（バキ）Ａ地区の道路は封鎖
（砂の里の忍）はっ
Yes, sir!
We must not assume
there's only one enemy!
（バキ）敵は１人だと
決めつけては ならん
No matter what happens,
maintain preparations for battle.
何があっても対処できるよう
臨戦態勢を緩めるな
We must be ready to respond!
Medical Team!
医療班
Set up a barrier and lead
all villagers inside! Hurry!
結界を張り 非戦闘員を
その中に誘導しろ 急げ
There must not be even one casualty!
Is that clear?!
１人たりとも犠牲になる者が
あってはならん いいな
We'll provide full support for Gaara...
No... for Kazekage-sama!
全力で我愛羅を…
いや 風影様を援護する
Gaara...
（カンクロウ）我愛羅…
（デイダラ）下から
邪魔されんのは興ざめだ
Interference from below really
puts a damper on things...
And besides...
それに…
I'm tired of looking at
your expressionless face.
お前の無表情も見飽きたしな
（我愛羅）ああ！
（デイダラ）フフッ
It's a doll
手のひらで食った粘土と
molded from detonating clay
that's got Chakra
チャクラを混ぜて作った
起爆粘土製の人形
and clay eaten by my palm
mixed together...
This specialty of mine...
中でもオハコは
...has C3 Chakra,
my most powerful Chakra,
おいらの最高レベルの
チャクラＣ３しーすりーを練り込んだ
built up inside.
The explosive power is
an exquisite work of art
爆発力が自慢の芸術大作
that I'm very proud of!
- What's that? Hey!
- Yeah, what the hell is it?
（砂の里の忍）なんだ あれは？
This is not good! Get back!
まずい 離れろ！
You're too late.
遅いね
フン！
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
Next time, I will finally develop
an ultra cool Jutsu!
次回は ついに俺様が
超かっこいい術を開発
The breathtaking arc begins
襲い来る暁たちを
バッタバッタとなぎ倒す
as I take down
the Akatsuki organization!
怒とうの展開が始まるぜ イテッ
What sort of nonsense are
you coming up with, you idiot!
何デタラメ
並べちゃってんのよ このバカ
あっ サクラちゃん
Oh, Sakura-chan...
あんた 私にフラれて 地味に
ラーメンすすってるだけじゃない
All you'll do is slurp on
some ramen noodles at the corner
after being dumped by me!
いいかげんなこと言ってると
Keep making stuff up,
and you'll get caught by the Police Force!
警務部隊に とっ捕まるわよ
でも俺だって目立ちたい
But I want some of
the spotlight too!
だまらっしゃい
しゃーんなろー！
Shut up, Shannaro!
次回
「ノルマクリアー」
Mission Cleared
Next time: "Mission Cleared"
Leaf Village
Sightseeing
Society
Society for Leaf Tourism.
Hello, everyone!
こんにちは 今回紹介するのは
Today, I will be introducing
木ノ葉隠れの里に
たくさんある演習場
the many Training Grounds in
the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
演習場では 日々実践により
忍術や体術 忍具の扱い方など
Shinobi basics such as Ninjutsu, Taijutsu,
and the use of Ninja Tools
are taught daily at the Training Grounds.
忍の基本が教えられるの
カカシ隊 第７班
Kakashi's unit, Team Seven made up
of Naruto, Sasuke-kun and I
ナルト サスケ君 私の３人は
started our training here
at the Third Training Grounds.
ここ 第３演習場で
演習を開始したわ
Our first exercise was a test
最初の演習は カカシ先生から
鈴を奪うというテスト
to see if we could take bells away
from Kakashi-sensei.
Oh my, I'm so young! How cute I was!
やだ 私ったら若い カワイイ
（カカシ）
仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ
People who don't cherish
their friends are absolute garbage.
The purpose of this test wasn't to
take away the bells.
（サクラ）このテストは
鈴を奪うことが目的ではなく
Rather, it seems it was to test
our teamwork
忍にとって いちばん大事な
チームワークを問う
テストだったんだって
which is the most important thing
for a Shinobi.
All of us in Team Seven passed
Kakashi-sensei's test
見事 カカシ先生の
テストに全員合格し
私たちは正式の忍者としての
スタートを切ったのでした
and from there,
we officially got our start as Ninja.
By the way, this is
Kakashi-sensei back in the day.
ちなみに これが昔のカカシ先生
And this is Kakashi Sensei now.
He hasn't changed much, has he?
で これが今
あんまし変わってないわね
I guess the only thing that has changed...
変わったのは
「イチャイチャパラダイス」から
is that now he's reading Make-Out Tactics
instead of Make-Out Paradise.
「イチャイチャタクティクス」に
なったことくらいかしら
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.